hi
嗨
this is going to be a quick video that
这将是一个简短的视频
will eventually drag on for 15 minutes
最终会拖上15分钟
on how to batch convert files using dark
浅谈如何使用DUCK批量转换文件
table
表格
i've been experimenting with developing
我一直在试验开发
photos in blender and quite a few people
搅拌机里的照片和相当多的人
asked how i get my camera files into
问我如何将我的相机文件放入
blender
搅拌机
simple i open dark table select the file
简单我打开暗桌选择文件
and click export
然后单击导出
job's done now i have a folder full of
工作完成了 现在我有一个满满的文件夹
exrs that's all there is to it if you
前任 这就是所有的事情 如果你
spend the time setting all the presets
花时间设置所有的预设
up
向上
two to be precise
准确地说是两个
one for the style the other one for the
一个用于样式 另一个用于
export options
导出选项
let's have a look at how to batch
让我们来看看如何批量处理
process or batch convert camera native
处理或批处理转换相机本机
data files also known as raw files
数据文件也称为原始文件
to get the most of our captures i'm
为了最大限度地利用我们的俘虏 我
going to try and lose as little data as
将尝试丢失尽可能少的数据
possible while still maintaining a
可能的同时仍保持
sensible file size
合理的文件大小
open extra as the name suggests is an
Open Extra顾名思义就是一个
open source file format developed by
由开发的开源文件格式
industrial light and magic yes the same
工业光和魔术 是的 是一样的
people who took part in all these films
参与了所有这些电影的人
we all like
我们都喜欢
all of them let's not get too hung up on
所有这些 让我们不要太纠结于
the file format for now let me just show
现在的文件格式让我来展示一下
you how to create presets for batch jobs
您将了解如何为批处理作业创建预设
in dark table and by the way if you
在黑暗的桌子上 顺便说一句 如果你
don't care about making your own presets
不关心自己做预置
i will include mine in the video
我会在视频中加入我的
description
描述
to import a style simply expand apply
要导入样式 只需展开应用
styles and hit import
样式和命中导入
to import a preset go to settings
要导入预设 请转到设置
presets and click import
预设并单击导入
before we do anything if this is the
在我们做任何事情之前 如果这是
first time you're running dive table
你第一次跑跳台
make sure you go to settings
请确保进入设置
processing
正在处理中
and set the auto apply chromatic
并设置自动应用色度
adaptation defaults to modern
默认改编为现代
then simply close the window
然后只需关闭窗口即可
okay let's import some captures
好的 让我们导入一些捕获
simply select your camera files and drag
只需选择您的摄像头文件并拖动
and drop them into the light table
然后把它们放到灯桌上
section
部分
now select any of them and move to
现在选择它们中的任何一个并移动到
darkroom we will create a style that we
暗房我们将创造一种我们
will be able to reuse later
将能够在以后重复使用
we have some of the modules active
我们有一些模块处于活动状态
already but we don't need all of them
已经有了 但我们不需要所有人
right now
现在就来
in my case for exporting linear rec709
在我的导出线性rec709的情况下
exrs i want only the basics with a
我只想要基本的 有一个
couple of extras
几个临时演员
the basics include the white balance
基本要素包括白平衡
module which is required for the mosaic
马赛克所需的模块
module
模块
we'll keep orientation
我们将保持定向
i don't really care about exposure at
我真的不关心曝光率在
this point
这一点
for color calibration module i want to
对于颜色校准模块 我想
bypass it
绕过它
but keep the clip negative rgb from
但要防止剪辑中的负片RGB
gamut box date
色域框日期
i don't want to sharpen
我不想磨砺
i don't want filmic rgb
我不想要电影里的RGB
and i want to set the output color
我想设置输出颜色
profile to linear rec 709
配置文件到线性记录709
that's it let's jump back to light table
就是这样 让我们跳回轻桌
time to save and bake those modules and
是时候保存和烘焙这些模块了
their settings into a style
他们的设置变成了一种样式
expand the apply styles module and
展开应用样式模块 然后
click create
单击创建
now we need to pay attention here a
现在我们需要在这里关注一个
little bit notice how not all of the
稍微注意一下 为什么不是所有的
modules are enabled for example we
模块已启用 例如我们
turned off the exposure module and we
关闭了曝光模块 我们
want to include that in our style so we
想要把它融入我们的风格中 所以我们
need to include the module that is off
需要包括关闭的模块
similarly we disabled filmic rgb that is
同样 我们禁用了胶片RGB 即
disabled the rest is pretty
残废的 其余的都很漂亮
self-explanatory include all the modules
不言而喻地包含所有模块
we want to apply to our imported files
我们想要应用于我们导入的文件
give it the name
给它起个名字
i'll call it exr out
我会把它叫作EXR
and click save
并点击保存
okay we've got our style done which
好的 我们已经做好了我们的发型
means that we can apply it to newly
意味着我们可以将其应用于新的
imported images
导入的图像
like that
就像这样
but we don't want to do this manually
但我们不想手动完成此操作
that's what we have dark table for let's
这就是我们有暗桌的原因 让我们
jump to export settings
跳转到导出设置
yours might be on the right side
你的可能是对的
depending on whose dark table you're on
这取决于你坐在哪张黑桌上
in the export settings we have a line
在导出设置中 我们有一行
called style
被称为Style
and in the drop down we can select our
在下拉列表中 我们可以选择我们的
style that we just created
我们刚刚创建的样式
this means that dark table will export a
这意味着暗桌子将输出一个
selected image and apply a chosen style
选定的图像并应用选定的样式
automatically
自动
other settings that we might need to
我们可能需要的其他设置
change for exr
更改为EXR
e x r
E x R
is bit depth
是位深度
and compression
和压缩
let's keep it on
让我们继续努力吧
biz
生意场
the target storage has a couple of neat
目标存储有几个整齐的
tricks up its sleeve you can sort of
把它的袖子翻起来 你可以说
program it to do interesting things
给它编程 让它做一些有趣的事情
type in the dollar sign and an open
键入美元符号和一个打开的
bracket
支架
to see all the possible operands
查看所有可能的操作数
the default one is file folder
默认文件夹为文件夹
then your export folder i'll call it my
那你的出口文件夹我就叫它我的
export
出口
exr
EXR
and
和
dollar sign open bracket file name
美元符号左方括号文件名
this will create an export exr folder in
这将在中创建一个导出EXR文件夹
the original folder where these files
这些文件所在的原始文件夹
are located
所处的位置
and then create an exr
然后创建一个EXR
based on its file name
根据其文件名
and lastly for profile
最后是配置文件
select linear rec709
选择线性记录709
i know we set this in the color profile
我知道我们在颜色配置文件中设置了这个
in the style
在风格上
but i just want to be sure that we are
但我只想确定我们是
definitely exporting linear rec709 exrs
确定正在导出线性rec709 exr
after all these settings are set i'm
在设置完所有这些设置后 我将
going to save another preset
要保存另一个预设
but this time is going to affect the
但这一次将影响到
export module i'm going to call it
导出模块 我要将其命名为
export
出口
underscore exr
带下划线EXR
okay
好吧
now just because we can i'm going to
现在 就因为我们可以 我就要
reset the module
重置模块
and i'm going to make a preset for a
我要做一个预置
simple jpeg export so i can switch
简单的jpeg导出 这样我就可以切换
between the two at will for the target
两者之间随意为靶子
storage i'm going to call it simply
我将简单地将其称为存储
jpeg
JPEG格式
i'm going to change the file format to
我要将文件格式更改为
and i want the images to fit into 3000
我想把这些图像放进3000
by 3000 size
乘以3000大小
set profile to srgb web save
将配置文件设置为sRGB Web存储
and let's keep the style at none
让我们保持不变的风格
i'm going to save this preset as well
我也要保存这个预置
call it export jpeg
我们称之为导出jpeg
now we can switch between these two at
现在 我们可以在这两者之间进行切换
will
将要
and we can export either exrs
我们可以出口任何一个EXR
or jpegs with a squeeze of a mouse
或Jpeg格式 只需轻轻一按鼠标
let's give it a go
让我们试一试吧
export
出口
and if we go back to the original folder
如果我们回到原来的文件夹
you will notice that there's a new jpeg
您会注意到有一个新的jpeg
folder
文件夹
with our crappy undeveloped jpegs
用我们糟糕的未开发的jpeg
okay
好吧
that goes straight to the bin
它会直接进入垃圾箱
that's pretty much for this video
这就是这段视频的主要内容
let me know if you're interested in my
如果你对我的
experiments with photos in blender don't
在搅拌机中进行照片实验不会
hesitate to drop a comment
不愿发表评论
i hope you learned something new today
我希望你今天学到了一些新东西
and i'll see you soon bye
我们很快就会再见了